Perth - Australia

Mobile: 0428 264 457 | **Email:** alex.tekheartproductions@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-smith-13a249151

CAREER JOURNEY

I am a self-taught and forever learning, passionate Full Stack Developer. Over the duration of my career, I have worked on projects ranging from simple web applications to mathematical models simulating the movement of trains within a governed physics model to assist with logistics planning. I thoroughly enjoy .NET and its frameworks and have become quite proficient with Vue.js for frontend development as well as the design and implementation of mathematical models within large scale projects.

In my spare time I take part in Cyber Security Research projects such as Bug Bounty and Vulnerability Disclosure programs.

CORE SKILLS TABLE

Key:

- 1: Aware of Functionality can perform basic support.
- 2: Basic Implementation Skills, may require some assistance.
- 3: Able to work independently, rare assistance required.
- 4: Able to work independently.
- 5: Comfortable to assist and guide others who are less familiar.

BACK END

Skill	Proficiency (1-5)
FastAPI / Django / Flask with sqlalchemy	5
Expressjs with sequelize or prisma	4.5
ASP .NET core with entity framework	4.5
Nodejs / Bun.js	5
Postgres	5
MongoDB	4
MySQL	4

FRONT END

Skill	Proficiency (1-5)
HTML, CSS, Javascript	5
Vue / Nuxt	5
React / Next.js	4
Svelte	3
.NET Blazor	3

Architecture & Security

Skill	Proficiency (1-5)
Network Management	4.5
Network Security	4

OSI & TCP / IP Models	5
VPN Configuration and Management	4.5
Network Topology Design and Implementation	4
Cloud Architecture and Security	4
Application Security Testing & Security Architecture Development	4
Penetration Testing & Bug Bounty Hunting	3
Kubernetes	4
Docker	4
Redis	5

EMPLOYMENT

Sales Representative and Store Maintenance | Guitar World Rockingham 2009 – 2012

- Assist customers of varying knowledge levels and experience within the music industry
- Ensure to always be "Representing" the store when engaging with customers or the public
- Demonstrate the assembly and disassembly of products, potentially breaking down the process for customers.
- Clean store and products on display
- Adhere to OHS standards particularly when working with Audio and Electrical equipment
- Sales of Products ranging from guitars, electric guitars, woodwind and orchestral to stage equipment and self-learning products (Books, DVDs etc.)
- Stock take
- Storage Management of products to ensure optimal usage of the space available
- Meet monthly KPI's

Sales Representative and Team Leader | BMJ Sports Perth 2013 – 2016

- Maximise earnings through KPI's and Commission based income
- Ensure to represent the client in question (4 clients split throughout the year) with integrity
- Greet potential customers as they pass and attempt to draw their attention toward the cause or product in question
- Build report with a customer efficiently
- Close a sale with integrity
- Transport large sums of money from the site of sales to the office.
- Set up and present products and signage relative to current client

Sales Representative | Carpet Call Rockingham

- 2016 2017
 - Attend customer's house and measure a basic layout of the desired area for flooring.
 - Create report with a customer be it in store, in the customers home or over the phone.
 - Supply a quote to the customer based on chosen product and area to be covered.
 - Follow up customers for satisfaction surveys and request contact details of referred friends or family.

Sales Representative and Web-Design | Something Goes Pop 2017 – 2019

- Design marketing strategies for the sales approach for pop-culture clothing lines and resale of pop-culture collectables.
- Build Web layouts and code e-commerce back-end for purchasing and creating orders for custom t-shirts
- Deliver orders within the "free delivery zone" to create a more personal, local business feel
- Close server points, terminate user profiles, delete all personal and professional information in compliance to local laws and performance directives.

Freelance Full-Stack Developer | Tekheart Productions 2019 – Current

- Apply previous sales experience to build report with potential clients and customers to "sell" a customer the product they are seeking with suggested features (additional or removal).
- Design customer layouts for best available option within desired time frame.
- Create a high level of trust between myself and the client given that majority of the time I manage and maintain personal, professional and client data.
- Maintain open communication between myself and clients
- Meet agreed upon milestones and where this may not be possible organise a meeting to discuss potential updates to milestones.
- Code both front-end and back-end of application adhering to agreed methodologies and documentation practices.
- Ensure the final product is functional and secure by avoiding insecure or deprecated methods, systems or third-party applications (including APIs, modules, etc,)

Bugcrowd & HackerOne

2021 - Current

- Search for security vulnerabilities within listed applications for programs
- Exercise integrity as to remain in scope without tampering with volatile systems that may cause excessive disruption for the target.
- Report Vulnerabilities
- Suggest (often provide) application fixes/patches relative to the vulnerability.
- Code automation tools for reconnaissance of an application and the target environment.
- Apply rigorous and intensive testing of infiltration and exploitation techniques to achieve Proof of Concept (PoC) to the greatest extent of exploitation possible from a given attack or chain of attacks.
- Accurate describe steps required to replicate a given exploitation of a vulnerability for verification by target or mitigation staff.

Software Developer / IT Support / Security Analyst

720 Management | Decimal Data Services

2022 - Current

- Assist with technical issues and support directives
- Assist with IT related issues within the corporate body over mediums such as Skype, Microsoft Teams, Phone etc...
- · Develop required software to enable business growth and stability
- Analyse IT security infrastructure
- Design, Pitch and Develop mitigation techniques and/or software solutions
- CI/CD techniques
- · Quarterly Penetration Testing

Full Stack Developer

ENCO Group Itd (in collaboration with Fortescue Metal Group)

2022 - Current

- Build, test and deploy API endpoints using Python FastAPI and ASP.NET.
- Build, test and deploy Frontend components and pages using VueJS and the Nuxtjs Framework
- Maintain Postgres databases.
- Plan and develop Mathematical ETA Model for logistics train operations.
- Implementation of said ETA Model in both Python and .Net.

EDUCATION

CompTIA Network+, Learning People (Currently Studying)

CompTIA Security+, Learning People (Currently Studying)

CompTIA Pentester+, Learning People (Currently Studying)

Introduction to Programming, RMIT University Advanced

Programming (Java), RMIT University

Ethical Hacking Zero to Master, Udemy (Zero To

Mastery) Game Programming C++ in Unreal Engine,

Udemy FullStack Developer, Codecademy React

Programming, Codecademy

Build Websites with HTML, CSS and GITHUB,

Codecademy SQL, Codecademy

JavaScript Foundations, Programming Hub

Advanced JavaScript, Programming Hub

Express JS, Programming Hub

Unity Certification, Programming Hub / Unity Learn

C++, Codecademy

C# Foundations, Programming Hub

CSS, Programming Hub

Responsive Web Design, Codecademy

Front-end Engineer, Codecademy

Back-end Engineer, Codecademy

Junior Developer Mission Path, Unity Learn

REFEREES

Name: Jarom Meurs

Company: ENCO Group Itd

Contact: jarom.meurs@enco.net.au

Association: Jarom was my Project Manager for both projects that I worked on at ENCO.

Name: Julien Sterk

Company: Fortescue Metal Group Contact: julien.sterk@fortescue.com

Association: Julien was the product leader for the "Inspector" project that I worked on whilst at

ENCO Group ltd and was my primary client contact.

Name: Blake Williams

Company: Williams' Water Sports

Contact:

Association: Built and maintain "William's Water Sports" Web application. Built with Vue.js,

ASP.Net, Postgres and Docker.

Name: Mathew Brown Company: Unknown

Contact:

Association: I have liaised with Mr Brown on several projects regarding Simulations and

Graphic Design in the Game's Industry.

Name: Brian Farrell

Company: 720 Management | Decimal Data Services

Contact: brian.farrell@livecricketdata.com

Association: Brian is the project lead for Decimal Data Services' Web Application services.